Noe Misael Nieto Arroyo

I have a M.Eng from UABC Mexicali where I worked with simulation sofware for solar cells, and a B.Eng in Electronics from ITP, Puebla. I have experience working as SysAdmin (Linux, Windows), backend & frontend developer, DBA. I've been working almost exclusively with FLOSS software such as Linux (15+ years), Python (+10 years), JavaScript, PHP, PostgreSQL, MySql and SQLite, among others, but I also know my way around the Windows/SQL Server/ASP.net stack.

Instructor and Speaker

Every now and then I participate in events mainly related to Free/Open Source Software, either as a speaker, trainer or attendee.

- Taller intensivo de Python November 4, 2017. 5 hours in Mexicali Baja California.
- X Jornada Académica, Social y Deportiva 2012 Nov. 12th-16th, Instituto Tecnológico de Oaxaca, Mexico; 20 hour python course for students of Software Engineering.
- Seminario de Aplicaciones de las Tecnologías de la Información y Comunicaciones - Sept. 3rd-7th, Instituto Tecnológico de Puebla, Mexico
 - Speaker. One 45 minute talk about basic multimedia applications with GStreamer.
 - Trainner. Five-hour Python course for newcomers.
 Attendants included students and teachers of the IT
 Academia of the ITP.
- FLISOL 2011 Introduction to the GStreamer multiedia Framework; April 9th, Puebla, Puebla;

Education

- June 2018 (expected); Master's degree in Engineering, UABC Mexicali. Estudio experimental y vía simulación de los materiales para celdas solares de tercera generación.
- September 2006; Arizona State University; Data Acquisition training seminar by JACMET group.
- September 2012; Electronics Engineering, Instituto Tecnológico de Puebla. Sistema de Vigilancia con Video sobre TCP/IP
- June 2000; Computer Programmer technician diploma, Universidad Popular Autónoma del Estado de Puebla.

Certifications

• SCRUM Master Accredited by International SCRUM Institute (May 2015).

Work Experience

- Social Reality Sysadmin, DBA, Backend; Mexicali (2015 ~ 2016).
- Valutech Outsourcing S.A. de C.V. Sysadmin/DBA;
 Mexicali (2013 ~ 2015).
- iServices de México Web/Python developer; Puebla (2009 ~ 2011).
- Honeywell Aerospace de Mexico Data Acquisition Engineer; Mexicali (2006 ~ 2008)
- Gameloft S de RL Multiplayer programmer; Mexicali (2006)
- Centro de ingenieria Instituto Nacional de Astrofísica Óptica y Electrónica - Internship. Embedded systems; Puebla (2005)
- FreeLance & IT Consultant Puebla, Mexico City, Oaxaca, Argentina (2000 ~ Now). Holokinesis Libros, Homeviva (Defunct), Venddo, Universidad Pedagógica Nacional, WAM - Ready2Fill.

Open source contributions

On 2018 I participated in Google Summer of Code enablig DevSim to do basic simulation of solar cells.

On 2007 I self-published a Gtk+3 programming manual in spanish, altough Gtk has gone trough a lot of chages, some parts are still relevant, so an updated version is on process.

Besides that, I'm an occasional FLOSS contributor on various projects and libraries.

Links

- Homepage
- Linked-In
- GitHub
- Email
- · Twitter